Motivation. Sofia Vergara, a Colombian actor in the American sitcom, Modern
Family, was doing an interview explaining that her 21 year old son had seen a video
of her many years earlier and said, Mom, you're the only person who's come to
America and your accent got worse. Her utterly charming response was, It's the
money, I don't have to do it anymore. In another interview, Oprah Winfrey asked why
her accent seems to be getting heavier, even though she's been living in America
for some time. Sofia explained that she actually does it for comedic effect, that
sometimes it was funnier to say you rather than you. She's very self-aware and has
excellent reasons for maintaining her brand. Over the years, however, we've
heard pretty much every excuse from people who have demonstrated that they are able
to create the sounds in isolation, but don't go on to the next step of
universally applying the rules. I feel uncomfortable. I don't understand the
rules. I wasn't thinking about it. I was focusing on what I was saying. It's not
possible. Why should I have to? People will laugh at me. I tried and can't. It's
not right. I forgot. I was rushing. Does pronunciation really matter? People say
it's just a detail, does it really matter? Isn't okay good enough for what's needed
and not worth the effort of going to the next level? We don't have that sound in my
language and we communicate just fine without it. This may be true, but if
you're, let's say, a doctor, don't you want your patients to know the difference
he's in urology and he's in neurology or we did a below-knee amputation and not we did
a baloney amputation. So yes, pronunciation matters.